<!--
 Copyright 2009 Sun Microsystems, Inc.  All rights reserved.
 Use is subject to license terms.
-->

<!--
 CDDL HEADER START

 The contents of this file are subject to the terms of the
 Common Development and Distribution License (the "License").
 You may not use this file except in compliance with the License.

 You can obtain a copy of the license at usr/src/OPENSOLARIS.LICENSE
 or http://www.opensolaris.org/os/licensing.
 See the License for the specific language governing permissions
 and limitations under the License.

 When distributing Covered Code, include this CDDL HEADER in each
 file and include the License file at usr/src/OPENSOLARIS.LICENSE.
 If applicable, add the following below this CDDL HEADER, with the
 fields enclosed by brackets "[]" replaced with your own identifying
 information: Portions Copyright [yyyy] [name of copyright owner]

 CDDL HEADER END
-->
<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<!-- ident	"@(#)entry8.xml	1.12	09/03/24 SMI" -->
<!DOCTYPE event_registry_properties SYSTEM "event_registry.dtd.1">
<event_registry_properties>
	<name>action</name>
	<item>Schedule a repair procedure to replace the affected CPU.  Use &#39;fmadm faulty&#39; to identify the module.</item>
	<name>description</name>
	<item>The number of errors associated with this CPU has exceeded acceptable levels.</item>
	<name>details</name>
	<item>This message indicates that the %DISTRO% Fault Manager has received reports
from a CPU indicating that correctable Instruction Cache Tag errors have 
occurred, and a CPU fault has been diagnosed. These errors are correctable, 
however they have occurred at a rate exceeding acceptable levels. There
should have been no operational impact on system or application activity 
from correctable errors.
&lt;P&gt;
The recommended service action for this event is to schedule replacement 
of the affected CPU at the earliest possible convenience. The faulted
CPU has been off-lined to prevent further disruption to system availability.
However, it is not intended nor recommended that the faulted FRU remain in 
the system for a prolonged period of time.
&lt;P&gt;
Follow the steps below to complete the recommended repair action.
&lt;P&gt;
&lt;B&gt;Step 1: &lt;/B&gt;Find the 36 character EVENT_ID string associated with the
fault.  
&lt;P&gt;
It can be located using several methods. Either fmdump (1M) or fmadm (1M) 
commands shown in Example 1.1 below, or extracted from the fault message 
displayed in the console output at the time of the fault.
&lt;P&gt;
Note: Be sure to get the correct 36 character EVENT_ID string if more
than one is listed.  You can identify the correct string by associating
the fault with the date and time stamp (highlighted in blue in Example 1.1 
below) from the fmdump output. fmadm faulty shows the EVENT_ID (highlighted
in red).
&lt;UL&gt;
&lt;B&gt;Example 1.1 - finding the EVENT_ID (36 character string):&lt;/B&gt;
&lt;/UL&gt;
&lt;UL&gt;&lt;PRE&gt;
# fmdump
TIME                 UUID                                 SUNW-MSG-ID
&lt;FONT COLOR=BLUE&gt;Mar 17 11:37:33.9073&lt;/FONT&gt; &lt;FONT COLOR=RED&gt;ecc65844-4f7f-4ef2-db97-eb4fd1648064&lt;/FONT&gt; AMD-8000-8L
Mar 17 15:16:52.1773 731c7264-0619-e4fd-fdc4-a58b9c1b9ffb AMD-8000-2F
Mar 20 10:50:54.7096 1eaa6704-1e0b-4ef9-9337-e14c108dfbec AMD-8000-AV
&lt;/PRE&gt;&lt;/UL&gt;
&lt;UL&gt;&lt;PRE&gt;
# fmadm faulty
   STATE RESOURCE / UUID
------------------------------------------------------------------------------
 faulted cpu:///cpuid=1
         &lt;FONT COLOR=RED&gt;ecc65844-4f7f-4ef2-db97-eb4fd1648064&lt;/FONT&gt;
------------------------------------------------------------------------------
&lt;/PRE&gt;&lt;/UL&gt;
&lt;B&gt;Step 2: &lt;/B&gt;Use the command; fmdump -v -u &lt;I&gt;EVENT_ID&lt;/I&gt;, to locate the faulty 
CPU Module, where &lt;I&gt;EVENT_ID&lt;/I&gt; consists of the 36 character string 
obtained in Step 1 above. FRU (highlighted in blue) See Example 2.1 below.
&lt;P&gt;
&lt;UL&gt;
&lt;B&gt;Example 2.1 - determining which FRU needs to be replaced:&lt;/B&gt;
&lt;/UL&gt;
&lt;UL&gt;&lt;PRE&gt;
# fmdump -v -u ecc65844-4f7f-4ef2-db97-eb4fd1648064
TIME                 UUID                                 SUNW-MSG-ID
Mar 17 11:37:33.9073 ecc65844-4f7f-4ef2-db97-eb4fd1648064 AMD-8000-8L
  100%  fault.cpu.amd.icachetag

        Problem in: hc:///motherboard=0/chip=0/cpu=1
           Affects: &lt;FONT COLOR=GREEN&gt;cpu:///cpuid=1&lt;/FONT&gt;
               FRU: &lt;FONT COLOR=BLUE&gt;hc:///motherboard=0/chip=0&lt;/FONT&gt;
&lt;/PRE&gt;&lt;/UL&gt;
&lt;P&gt;
&lt;B&gt;Step 3: &lt;/B&gt;Identify the FRU that needs to be replaced.
&lt;P&gt;
In our example, the service action would be to replace CPU0, as the chip 
identified in the string following the &#39;FRU:&#39; label (highlighted in blue) 
in Example 2 above, is hc///motherboard=0/chip=0.
&lt;P&gt;
The term &#39;chip&#39; used in the output above can also be used to refer
to a processor or CPU chip, hence &#39;chip=x&#39; equates to &#39;CPU chipx&#39;.
Note that the cpuid refers to a logical CPU number within the CPU 
chip.
&lt;P&gt;
For all Sun AMD based systems;
&lt;P&gt;
chip=x maps to the processor chip labeled CPUx within the system.
&lt;P&gt;
For example:
&lt;UL&gt;
chip=0 maps to the physical location labeled; CPU0
&lt;BR&gt;chip=1 maps to the physical location labeled; CPU1
&lt;P&gt;
&lt;/UL&gt;
&lt;B&gt;Step 4: &lt;/B&gt;Replace the faulty FRU (and reboot the system)
&lt;P&gt;
Refer to the service label or hardware maintenance manual for correct 
replacement procedures.
&lt;P&gt;
&lt;B&gt;Step 5: &lt;/B&gt;Update the Fault Manager&#39;s resource cache to indicate
that no problems are present in the resources that had been diagnosed
faulty and subsequently replaced in Step 4. Shown in Example 5.1
&lt;P&gt;
Once the CPU has been physically replaced and the system rebooted,
you must invoke the &#39;fmadm repair&#39; command using the UUID (Universally 
Unique IDentifier) to identify the repaired FRU.  The UUID is synonymous
with the EVENT_ID (highlighted in red) in Example 1.1 above.
&lt;UL&gt;
&lt;B&gt;Example 5.1 - Updating the Fault Manager&#39;s resource cache:&lt;/B&gt;
&lt;/UL&gt;
&lt;UL&gt;&lt;PRE&gt;
# fmadm repair ecc65844-4f7f-4ef2-db97-eb4fd1648064
# fmadm: recorded repair to ecc65844-4f7f-4ef2-db97-eb4fd1648064
&lt;/PRE&gt;&lt;/UL&gt;
&lt;B&gt;Step 6: &lt;/B&gt;Verify the repaired resource is no longer faulty
&lt;P&gt;
Use the %DISTRO% command &#39;fmadm faulty&#39; to display all faulted resources
in the system.  Confirm that the repaired resource is no longer listed
as faulted shown in Example 6.1.
&lt;P&gt;
&lt;/PRE&gt;&lt;/UL&gt;
&lt;P&gt;
&lt;UL&gt;
&lt;B&gt;Example 6.1 - verifying the repaired resource is no longer faulty:&lt;/B&gt;
&lt;/UL&gt;
&lt;UL&gt;&lt;PRE&gt;
# fmadm faulty
   STATE RESOURCE / UUID
------------------------------------------------------------------------------
&lt;/PRE&gt;&lt;/UL&gt;
&lt;P&gt;
&lt;B&gt;Step 7: &lt;/B&gt;Place the CPU back into the active configuration
&lt;P&gt;
Once you have completed the repair action, and told the fault manager 
that the FRU has been repaired, it may still be necessary to tell %DISTRO% 
to use the affected system resource.  If the &lt;B&gt;Automated Response&lt;/B&gt; 
described above in this article was; &quot;An attempt will be made to remove 
this CPU from service.&quot;, you will need to place the CPU back into the 
active configuration and verify that the CPU has been returned to service.
&lt;P&gt;
To place the CPU back into the active configuration, you will need to 
know the logical CPU number that was faulted.  The logical CPU number 
was identified in the fmdump output following the label &#39;Affects:&#39; 
(highlighted in green) in Example 2.1 above. You can also identify a 
CPU that is still considered faulted by %DISTRO% using the psrinfo (1M) 
command shown in Example 7.1 below.  
&lt;UL&gt;
&lt;B&gt;Example 7.1 - identifying the logical CPU number that was faulted:&lt;/B&gt;
&lt;PRE&gt;
# psrinfo
0       on-line   since 03/17/2006 11:04:16
1       faulted   since 03/17/2006 11:37:33
2       on-line   since 03/17/2006 11:08:52
3       on-line   since 03/17/2006 11:04:23 
&lt;/UL&gt;
&lt;P&gt;&lt;/PRE&gt;
&lt;P&gt;
Place the faulted CPU back into the active configuration using the psradm 
(1M) command; &#39;psradm -F -n x&#39; where x is the logical cpuid.  As logical CPU 
1 was identified as the faulted CPU, the psradm (1M) command shown in Example 
7.2 below will return it to the active configuration.
&lt;UL&gt;
&lt;B&gt;Example 7.2 - returning the repaired CPU to the active configuration:&lt;/B&gt;
&lt;PRE&gt;
# psradm -F -n 1
&lt;/UL&gt;&lt;/PRE&gt;
&lt;P&gt;
&lt;B&gt;Step 8: &lt;/B&gt;Verify the CPU is in use by the system.
&lt;P&gt;
To verify that the CPU has been returned to service, use the %DISTRO% 
command psrinfo (1M). See Example 8.1 below.
&lt;P&gt;
&lt;UL&gt;
&lt;B&gt;Example 8.1 - verifying the CPU has returned to service:&lt;/B&gt;
&lt;/UL&gt;
&lt;UL&gt;&lt;PRE&gt;
# psrinfo
0       on-line   since 03/17/2006 11:08:55
1       on-line   since 03/17/2006 11:09:50
2       on-line   since 03/17/2006 11:08:52
3       on-line   since 03/17/2006 11:08:56 
&lt;/UL&gt;&lt;/PRE&gt;</item>
	<name>impact</name>
	<item>Performance of this system may be affected.</item>
	<name>response</name>
	<item>An attempt will be made to remove this CPU from service.</item>
	<name>title</name>
	<item>CPU errors exceeded acceptable levels</item>
</event_registry_properties>
