<!--
 Copyright 2009 Sun Microsystems, Inc.  All rights reserved.
 Use is subject to license terms.
-->

<!--
 CDDL HEADER START

 The contents of this file are subject to the terms of the
 Common Development and Distribution License (the "License").
 You may not use this file except in compliance with the License.

 You can obtain a copy of the license at usr/src/OPENSOLARIS.LICENSE
 or http://www.opensolaris.org/os/licensing.
 See the License for the specific language governing permissions
 and limitations under the License.

 When distributing Covered Code, include this CDDL HEADER in each
 file and include the License file at usr/src/OPENSOLARIS.LICENSE.
 If applicable, add the following below this CDDL HEADER, with the
 fields enclosed by brackets "[]" replaced with your own identifying
 information: Portions Copyright [yyyy] [name of copyright owner]

 CDDL HEADER END
-->
<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<!-- ident	"@(#)entry2.xml	1.20	09/03/30 SMI" -->
<!DOCTYPE event_registry_properties SYSTEM "event_registry.dtd.1">
<event_registry_properties>
	<name>action</name>
	<item>Schedule a repair procedure to replace the affected memory module. Use 'fmadm faulty' to identify the memory module.</item>
	<name>description</name>
	<item>The number of correctable errors associated with this memory module has exceeded acceptable levels.</item>
	<name>details</name>
	<item>This message indicates that the %DISTRO% Fault Manager has received reports
of single bit correctable errors from a Memory Module at a rate exceeding
acceptable levels, and a Memory Module fault has been diagnosed. No
data has been lost, and pages of the affected Memory Module are being
retired as errors are encountered. 
&lt;P&gt;
The recommended service action for this event is to schedule replacement 
of the affected Memory Module at the earliest possible convenience. The 
errors are correctable in nature so they do not present an immediate threat
to system availability. 
&lt;P&gt;
Follow the steps below to complete the recommended repair action.
&lt;P&gt;
&lt;B&gt;Step 1: &lt;/B&gt;Find the 36 character EVENT_ID string associated with the
fault.  
&lt;P&gt;
It can be located using several methods. Either fmdump (1M) or fmadm (1M) 
commands shown in Example 1.1 below, or extracted from the fault message 
displayed in the console output at the time of the fault.
&lt;P&gt;
Note: Be sure to get the correct 36 character EVENT_ID string if more
than one is listed.  You can identify the correct string by associating
the fault with the date and time stamp (highlighted in blue in Example 1.1 
below) from the fmdump output. fmadm faulty shows the EVENT_ID (highlighted
in red).
&lt;P&gt;
&lt;UL&gt;
&lt;B&gt;Example 1.1 - finding the EVENT_ID (36 character string):&lt;/B&gt;
&lt;/UL&gt;
&lt;UL&gt;&lt;PRE&gt;
# fmdump
TIME                 UUID                                 SUNW-MSG-ID
&lt;FONT COLOR=BLUE&gt;Mar 17 15:16:52.1773&lt;/FONT&gt; &lt;FONT COLOR=RED&gt;731c7264-0619-e4fd-fdc4-a58b9c1b9ffb&lt;/FONT&gt; AMD-8000-2F
Mar 18 12:26:46.0362 ab688055-6049-60aa-817b-cf25406dac43 AMD-8000-67
Mar 20 10:50:54.7096 1eaa6704-1e0b-4ef9-9337-e14c108dfbec AMD-8000-AV
&lt;/PRE&gt;&lt;/UL&gt;
&lt;UL&gt;&lt;PRE&gt;
# fmadm faulty
    STATE RESOURCE / UUID
-----------------------------------------------------------------------
degraded mem:///motherboard=0/chip=0/memory-controller=0/dimm=0
         &lt;FONT COLOR=RED&gt;731c7264-0619-e4fd-fdc4-a58b9c1b9ffb&lt;/FONT&gt;
-----------------------------------------------------------------------
&lt;/PRE&gt;&lt;/UL&gt;
&lt;B&gt;Step 2: &lt;/B&gt;Use the command; fmdump -v -u &lt;I&gt;EVENT_ID&lt;/I&gt;, to locate the faulty 
memory module, where &lt;I&gt;EVENT_ID&lt;/I&gt; consists of the 36 character string 
obtained in Step 1 above. FRU (highlighted in blue) See Example 2.1 below.
&lt;P&gt;
&lt;UL&gt;
&lt;B&gt;Example 2.1 - determining which FRU needs to be replaced:&lt;/B&gt;
&lt;/UL&gt;
&lt;UL&gt;&lt;PRE&gt;
# fmdump -v -u 731c7264-0619-e4fd-fdc4-a58b9c1b9ffb
TIME                 UUID                                 SUNW-MSG-ID
Mar 17 15:16:52.1773 731c7264-0619-e4fd-fdc4-a58b9c1b9ffb AMD-8000-2F
  100%  fault.memory.dimm_sb

        Problem in: hc:///motherboard=0/chip=0/memory-controller=0/dimm=0
           Affects: mem:///motherboard=0/chip=0/memory-controller=0/dimm=0
               FRU: &lt;FONT COLOR=BLUE&gt;hc:///motherboard=0/chip=0/memory-controller=0/dimm=0&lt;/FONT&gt;
&lt;/PRE&gt;&lt;/UL&gt;
&lt;P&gt;
&lt;B&gt;Step 3: &lt;/B&gt;Identify the FRU that needs to be replaced.
&lt;p&gt;
In our example, the service action would be to replace memory module 0 
associated with CPU0 (chip=0), as the memory module identified in the 
string following the &#39;FRU:&#39; label (highlighted in blue) in Example 2.1 above, 
is hc///motherboard=0/chip=0/memory-controller=0/dimm=0.
&lt;p&gt;
The term &#39;chip&#39; used in the output above can also be used to refer
to a processor or CPU chip, hence &#39;chip=x&#39; equates to &#39;CPU chipx&#39;.
Note that the cpuid refers to a logical CPU number within the CPU 
chip.
&lt;P&gt;
For all Sun AMD based systems;
&lt;P&gt;
chip=x maps to the processor chip labeled CPUx within the system.
&lt;P&gt;
For example:
&lt;UL&gt;
chip=0 maps to the physical location labeled; CPU0
&lt;BR&gt;chip=1 maps to the physical location labeled; CPU1
&lt;P&gt;
Once you have identified the correct CPU location, you then need to 
&lt;br&gt;identify it&#39;s corresponding memory module.
&lt;p&gt;
Please reference the following SRDB (Symptom Resolution Data Base)
&lt;br&gt;link for the labeling of your Platforms Memory Module(s).
&lt;p&gt;
&lt;a href=http://sunsolve.sun.com/search/document.do?assetkey=1-25-85497-1&amp;searchclause=&gt;Memory Labeling&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;/UL&gt;
&lt;B&gt;Step 4: &lt;/B&gt;Replace the faulty FRU (and reboot the system)
&lt;P&gt;
Refer to the service label or hardware maintenance manual for correct 
replacement procedures.
&lt;P&gt;
&lt;B&gt;Step 5: &lt;/B&gt;Update the Fault Manager&#39;s resource cache to indicate
that no problems are present in the resources that had been diagnosed
faulty and subsequently replaced in Step 4. Shown in Example 5.1
&lt;P&gt;
Once the Memory Modules have been physically replaced and the system rebooted,
you must invoke the &#39;fmadm repair&#39; command using the UUID (Universally 
Unique IDentifier) to identify the repaired FRU.  The UUID is synonymous
with the EVENT_ID (highlighted in red) in Example 1.1 above.
&lt;P&gt;
&lt;UL&gt;
&lt;B&gt;Example 5.1 - Updating the Fault Manager&#39;s resource cache:&lt;/B&gt;
&lt;/UL&gt;
&lt;UL&gt;&lt;PRE&gt;
# fmadm repair 731c7264-0619-e4fd-fdc4-a58b9c1b9ffb
# fmadm: recorded repair to 731c7264-0619-e4fd-fdc4-a58b9c1b9ffb
&lt;/PRE&gt;&lt;/UL&gt;
&lt;P&gt;
&lt;B&gt;Step 6: &lt;/B&gt;Reset the Faulted Page Counters.
&lt;P&gt;
Once the fmadm repair &amp;lt;UUID&amp;gt has completed reset the Faulted Page  counter,
&lt;br&gt;you must invoke the &#39;fmadm reset&#39; command shown in Example 6.1 below.
&lt;br&gt;The required action in this step is temporary. When this becomes automated
&lt;br&gt;this article will be updated to reflect these changes.
&lt;P&gt;
&lt;UL&gt;
&lt;B&gt;Example 6.1 - Reset Faulted Page Counters&lt;/B&gt;
&lt;/UL&gt;
&lt;UL&gt;&lt;PRE&gt;
# fmadm reset eft
&lt;/PRE&gt;&lt;/UL&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
Note: By resetting the Faulted Page Counters, this will reset ALL diagnosis
&lt;br&gt;state for the diagnosis engine. All event history will be lost. All
&lt;br&gt;Already diagnosed faults will continue to appear in fmadm faulty. Before
&lt;br&gt;resetting capture the outputs from fmstat -m eft, fmstat -s -m eft.
&lt;p&gt;
&lt;B&gt;Step 7: &lt;/B&gt;Verify the repaired resource is no longer faulty
&lt;P&gt;
Use the %DISTRO% command &#39;fmadm faulty&#39; to display all faulted resources
&lt;br&gt;in the system.  Confirm that the repaired resource is no longer listed
&lt;br&gt;as faulted shown in Example 7.1.
&lt;P&gt;
&lt;/PRE&gt;&lt;/UL&gt;
&lt;P&gt;
&lt;UL&gt;
&lt;B&gt;Example 7.1 - verifying the repaired resource is no longer faulty:&lt;/B&gt;
&lt;/UL&gt;
&lt;UL&gt;&lt;PRE&gt;
# fmadm faulty
   STATE RESOURCE / UUID
-------- ----------------------------------------------------------------------
&lt;/PRE&gt;&lt;/UL&gt;</item>
	<name>impact</name>
	<item>Total system memory capacity has been reduced (where supported).</item>
	<name>response</name>
	<item>Pages of memory associated with this memory module may have been removed from service, up to a limit which has now been reached.</item>
	<name>title</name>
	<item>Memory module correctable errors exceeding acceptable levels</item>
</event_registry_properties>
