<!--
 Copyright 2007 Sun Microsystems, Inc.  All rights reserved.
 Use is subject to license terms.
-->

<!--
 CDDL HEADER START

 The contents of this file are subject to the terms of the
 Common Development and Distribution License (the "License").
 You may not use this file except in compliance with the License.

 You can obtain a copy of the license at usr/src/OPENSOLARIS.LICENSE
 or http://www.opensolaris.org/os/licensing.
 See the License for the specific language governing permissions
 and limitations under the License.

 When distributing Covered Code, include this CDDL HEADER in each
 file and include the License file at usr/src/OPENSOLARIS.LICENSE.
 If applicable, add the following below this CDDL HEADER, with the
 fields enclosed by brackets "[]" replaced with your own identifying
 information: Portions Copyright [yyyy] [name of copyright owner]

 CDDL HEADER END
-->

<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<!-- ident	"@(#)entry6.xml	1.3	07/01/30 SMI" -->
<!DOCTYPE event_registry_properties SYSTEM "event_registry.dtd.1">
<event_registry_properties>
	<name>title</name>
	<item>Sun Crypto Accelerator 4000 Firmware May Be Defective Or Hardware May Be Faulty</item>

	<name>description</name>
	<item>The Solaris Fault Manager has determined that a firmware
defect or hardware fault was detected on Sun Crypto Accelerator 4000
card which requires repair action.</item>

	<name>response</name>
	<item>The driver has been disabled and unregistered as a hardware
provider to the Solaris Cryptographic Framework.</item>

	<name>impact</name>
	<item>The card will no longer function as a network device or
cryptographic accelerator until the problem has been resolved.</item>

	<name>action</name>
	<item>Run the SCA4000 diagnostic tests on the
adapter (rsrc) identified in the fmdump(1M) output as instructed in the
Sun Crypto Accelerator 4000 Board Installation and Users Guide.
&lt;br&gt;&lt;br&gt;
If diagnostic tests fail, perform a keystore backup and schedule a
repair procedure to replace the affected adapter.
&lt;br&gt;&lt;br&gt;
Run &lt;tt&gt;pkgchk -n SUNWvcafw&lt;/tt&gt; to ensure that the latest firmware package is
correctly installed and has been downloaded to the
adapter (rsrc) identified in the fmdump(1M) output as instructed in the
Sun
Crypto Accelerator 4000 Board Installation and Users Guide.
&lt;br&gt;&lt;br&gt;
If the latest firmware has already been correctly installed, contact
Sun for support</item>

	<name>details</name>
	<item>
The Message ID:&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&lt;font size="+1"&gt;&lt;tt&gt;&lt;b&gt;%MSGID%&lt;/b&gt;&lt;/tt&gt;&lt;/font&gt;
indicates diagnosis has determined
that the firmware running on the SCA4000 PCI adapter is
defective or the hardware is faulty.  The SCA4000 (vca) driver
has disabled the network and cryptographic accelerator
interfaces.  Insure that the latest firmware package
(SUNWvcafw) is installed on the system and that the firmware supplied
with that package (sca4000fw) has been downloaded to the
card.  The version 2.0 driver only supports version 2.0
firmware.
&lt;br&gt;&lt;br&gt;
Refer to the Sun Crypto Accelerator 4000 Board Installation and Users
Guide for information on determining version of firmware currently
running on the card and downloading the correct version if necessary.
&lt;br&gt;&lt;br&gt;
After installing the latest firmware on the card, diagnostic
tests
should be run to isolate the source of the problem.  If
diagnostics fail, the problem is
most likely due
to a hardware fault and the card should be replaced.  If
diagnostic tests pass and the problem
persists, contact Sun for support.
&lt;br&gt;&lt;br&gt;
After installing the latest firmware version or replacing the card, the
network and
cryptographic
accelerator interfaces may be brought back into service using the
fmadm(1M) command:
&lt;br&gt;&lt;br&gt;
fmadm repair &amp;lt;EVENT-ID&amp;gt;
	</item>

</event_registry_properties>
