<!--
 Copyright 2008 Sun Microsystems, Inc.  All rights reserved.
 Use is subject to license terms.
-->

<!--
 CDDL HEADER START

 The contents of this file are subject to the terms of the
 Common Development and Distribution License (the "License").
 You may not use this file except in compliance with the License.

 You can obtain a copy of the license at usr/src/OPENSOLARIS.LICENSE
 or http://www.opensolaris.org/os/licensing.
 See the License for the specific language governing permissions
 and limitations under the License.

 When distributing Covered Code, include this CDDL HEADER in each
 file and include the License file at usr/src/OPENSOLARIS.LICENSE.
 If applicable, add the following below this CDDL HEADER, with the
 fields enclosed by brackets "[]" replaced with your own identifying
 information: Portions Copyright [yyyy] [name of copyright owner]

 CDDL HEADER END
-->
<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<!-- ident	"@(#)entry0.xml	1.11	08/04/10 SMI" -->
<!DOCTYPE event_registry_properties SYSTEM "event_registry.dtd.1">
<event_registry_properties>
	<name>action</name>
	<item>Save the error information from the console, if possible. Log any 
ereports, panic strings and other information appearing on the system
and have it available If placing a service call.  Please look for 
diagnostic messages upon reboot.</item>
	<name>description</name>
	<item>Errors have been detected that require a reboot to ensure system integrity.</item>
	<name>details</name>
	<item>&lt;b&gt;&lt;FONT COLOR=RED&gt;PLEASE NOTE:  THIS ERROR EVENT IS NOT A DIAGNOSIS OF THE FAULT OR 
ERROR THAT RESULTED IN THE REBOOT.  THIS IS AN INFORMATIONAL 
MESSAGE INDICATING THAT THE SYSTEM IS ATTEMPTING TO REBOOT AND 
THE ACTION REQUESTED IS TO COLLECT ANY ADDITIONAL ERROR INFORMATION THAT MAY EXIST.&lt;/FONT&gt;&lt;/b&gt;
&lt;p&gt;

The Message ID:&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;
&lt;font size=&quot;+1&quot;&gt;&lt;tt&gt;&lt;b&gt;%MSGID%&lt;/b&gt;&lt;/tt&gt;&lt;/font&gt;
indicates errors detected by the Solaris kernel required immediate
reboot to preserve system integrity.
&lt;p&gt;
This error event could be caused by a hardware fault, such as a 
defective component or firmware incompatibility, or a software event, 
such as a bad patch, misconfiguration, or downrev device driver.  
This list is not an exhaustive list of possible reasons for the reboot, 
but merely some suggestions as to why it took place.
&lt;p&gt;  
If the system environment has been modified immediately prior to the 
error event (added hardware, patched the configuration, new firmware, 
etc), consider that the change may be the actual cause of this reboot 
event and if logging a service call, inform the engineer of this 
change so it can be investigated.
&lt;p&gt;
The system will attempt to save the error information and then perform
diagnosis as the system reboots. It can be examined using several methods. 
Use the fmdump (1M) or fmadm (1M) commands, or examine the fault 
message displayed in the console output at the time of the fault.
&lt;p&gt;
In the event that the system is unable to save or process the additional
information and system diagnosis fails, the error report information from the system
console may be useful in trying to manually diagnose a system failure.
Please have this information available when placing a service call for 
additional help.
&lt;P&gt;
&lt;b&gt;Please Note -&lt;/b&gt; On some system platforms there could be additional 
information that may disclose a hardware fault, see the following:
&lt;P&gt;
On Sun SPARC Enterprise Mx000 systems,  
please check the output of &quot;showstatus&quot; and &quot;fmdump&quot; from the xscfu for 
possible hardware faults.
&lt;P&gt;
On Sun Fire 12K, 15K, 20K and E25K systems, please check the output of  
&quot;showlogs -E -p e list 3&quot; from the main system controller for 
information about possible hardware faults.
&lt;P&gt;
On Sun Fire 3800, 48x0, 6800, v1280, E2900, E4900, E6900 and Netra 1280/1290 systems, 
please check the output of &quot;showlogs -v&quot; from the main system controller 
for information about possible hardware faults.

&lt;p&gt;</item>
	<name>impact</name>
	<item>The system will sync files, save a crash dump if needed, and reboot</item>
	<name>po-action</name>
	<item>Save the error summary below in case telemetry cannot be saved</item>
	<name>response</name>
	<item>Solaris will attempt to save and diagnose the error telemetry</item>
	<name>title</name>
	<item>Errors require a reboot</item>
</event_registry_properties>
